<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel><title><![CDATA[Bits, Bips and Bricks]]></title><description><![CDATA[Tech, Finance and Real Estate]]></description><link>https://www.bitsbipsbricks.com/</link><image><url>https://www.bitsbipsbricks.com/favicon.png</url><title>Bits, Bips and Bricks</title><link>https://www.bitsbipsbricks.com/</link></image><generator>Ghost 5.58</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 12:16:27 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.bitsbipsbricks.com/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[The World Has Changed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Editor's Note: This was written in September 2022. At the time, I wanted to add more about what I thought image generators would be used for, and then I procrastinated—a lot. But I've decided to publish this version for posterity. The world has changed, and still almost nobody knows it yet.
]]></description><link>https://www.bitsbipsbricks.com/imagegenerationengines/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6316b3df9762b1003d77608a</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2023 00:53:49 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Editor&apos;s Note: This was written in September 2022. At the time, I wanted to add more about what I thought image generators would be used for, and then I procrastinated&#x2014;a lot. But I&apos;ve decided to publish this version for posterity. The world has changed, and still almost nobody knows it yet.</p><p>Today is September 6th, 2022. The three main image generation engines are DALL-E 2, Stable Diffusion, and Midjourney. (The date is important. The leading engines could be different a week from now.) Two months ago, the creation of digital artwork cost $100&apos;s dollars or $1000&apos;s dollars an image and photography costs $10&apos;s and $1000&apos;s per image. Today, the creation of digital images costs cents. Images can now be generated in seconds, by giving an image generation engine a text prompt and by fiddling with two or three simple parameters.</p><p>DALL-E 2 was released on July 20th, 2022. OpenAI, one of the world&apos;s leading research laboratories, created it. OpenAI has XX[1] employees. It was closed-sourced and available initially only to beta testers on the waitlist. OpenAI distorted any faces in images making it hard to be used for deep fakes. Stability AI released Stable Diffusion on August 22nd, 2022, 33 days later. Stable Diffusion is open source, can be run on a consumer GPU, and doesn&apos;t blur faces like DALL-E 2. Stability AI, as of August 12th, 2022, has 75 employees.</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card"><img src="https://www.bitsbipsbricks.com/content/images/2023/07/out-1.png" class="kg-image" alt loading="lazy" width="512" height="512"></figure><p>The images aren&#x2019;t prefect. They still gave off a weird vibe. And giving the right words to get the image you want (prompt engineering[2]) is still a bit finicky. But an hour after I started playing with Stable Diffusion, I was able to create this image of an Canadian Flag and an Astronaut on the moon. (So can you with [Stable Diffusion](<a href="https://replicate.com/p/xipb7ajpnretfmu42z3yxnhwuu?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">https://replicate.com/p/xipb7ajpnretfmu42z3yxnhwuu</a>) on commit a9758cbfbd5f with width 512 height 512 prompt Neil Armstrong on the Moon Canadian Flag num_outputs 4 guidance_scale 7 prompt_strength 0.8 num_inference_steps 129 and seed 47692).</p><p>More:</p><ul><li>Soon for videos, etc</li><li>Fundamentally, a different medium</li><li>Deepfakes</li><li>Creative labour</li><li>New art created (Comic book etc)</li><li>Programmatic creation (See what clothes would look like on you?, What products look like your home?)</li><li>Meaning of non-human-created artwork?</li><li>Creative work of curation??</li><li>Can&apos;t be put back in the box. This felt different. We were/aren&apos;t ready.</li><li><strong>We won&apos;t be ready for the next one</strong></li></ul><p>[1] I didn&apos;t find the number at the time and couldn&apos;t find the exact number now<br>[2] I&apos;ve changed my mind about what prompt engineering is. <a href="https://mitchellh.com/writing/prompt-engineering-vs-blind-prompting?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">Prompt Engineering vs. Blind Prompting &#x2014; Mitchell Hashimoto</a></p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why You Should Own YourName.com]]></title><description><![CDATA[In less than 20 minutes and for less than $20, you can own your own plot of land on the internet.]]></description><link>https://www.bitsbipsbricks.com/why-you-should-own-yourname-com/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63b7a4e857d46f003d7fc72b</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 04:39:48 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1573867639040-6dd25fa5f597?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=MnwxMTc3M3wwfDF8c2VhcmNofDE0fHx3ZWJzaXRlfGVufDB8fHx8MTY3Mjk3OTcxMA&amp;ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;q=80&amp;w=2000" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1573867639040-6dd25fa5f597?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=MnwxMTc3M3wwfDF8c2VhcmNofDE0fHx3ZWJzaXRlfGVufDB8fHx8MTY3Mjk3OTcxMA&amp;ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;q=80&amp;w=2000" alt="Why You Should Own YourName.com"><p>These days there are many places to hang your digital shingle&#x2014; Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, Mastodon, Reddit, etc. And there are many ways to communicate&#x2014; Messenger, Instagram DMs and WhatsApp and others not owned by Meta, like iMessage, Slack and Discord.</p><p>But you own none of these [1]. It&apos;s like building a business in a building you don&apos;t own. Maybe it&apos;s the right move, but your landlord can always decide to kick you out at renewal time. There&apos;s nothing wrong with posting or messaging on platforms you don&apos;t own. But you should have at least one place where to control your access to the platform. Check the terms of your lease. You can get kicked off Facebook, banned from Twitter, and have your Gmail account suspended for any or no reason.</p><p>You should go out today to buy <code>FirstNameLastName.com</code> if it&apos;s available. If it&apos;s not available, then buy another version of your name, like <code>FirstNameMiddleNameLastName.com</code>, <code>FirstNameMiddleInitialLastName.co</code> or <code>FirstNameLastName.site</code> . I would recommend searching for available domains using <a href="https://www.namecheap.com/domains/registration/results/?type=beast&amp;domain=&amp;ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">NameCheap&apos;s Beast Mode Search</a>, which lets you search 100&apos;s TLD&apos;s at the same time. And then &#xA0;buying the domain &#xA0;on <a href="https://www.hover.com/?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">Hover</a>. Hover is a domain name registry which is easy to use and has amazing customer service. Customer service is an very important to consider when picking a domain name registry because you&apos;ll be a customer for possiblly decades.</p><p>It&apos;ll take less than 20 minutes and cost less than $20. If you don&apos;t do anything else, you should buy this domain. Then, you can procrastinate for years before you do anything else.</p><p>If you want, you can buy <code>LastName.com</code>, so that send email from <code>FirstName@LastName.com</code>. Using <a href="https://www.hover.com/?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">Hover</a>, you can set up this email and forward it to your normal Gmail account so that nothing about your day-to-day emailing experience will change. So even if your Gmail account gets banned, you&apos;ll have access to <code>FirstName@LastName.com</code>. How many sites is your Gmail account the credentials for? <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2022/08/21/technology/google-surveillance-toddler-photo.html?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">What happens if Father Google wakes up on the wrong side of the bed?</a> Also, sending email from <code>FirstName@LastName.com</code> is cool.</p><p>If you are a software engineer or a designer or do anything creative, you probably have some (or should have some) artifacts of your work you can share to with others. Your personal website is a great place to share them. Even if they natively live on GitHub, Vsco or Vimeo, you can link to and back them up here. I am using <a href="https://ghost.org/?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">Ghost</a> for this website and using <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">Jekyll</a> for my personal website <a href="https://ramvasuthevan.ca/?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">ramvasuthevan.ca</a>[2] .</p><p>Remember, you can set up your custom email and personal website anytime, but time might be running out to register <code>FirstNameLastName.com</code> . Go do it now.</p><p>[1] You do control your phone number. In general, phone companies won&apos;t seize your phone number; you take it with you when you change carriers, and it&apos;s a safe bet that it&apos;ll still work 10 years from now. Which is why social media apps ask you to upload your contact book.<br>[2] I procrastinated for years on building this site. But inspired by this tweet, I decided to just go for it and host some <a href="https://github.com/RamVasuthevan/Personal-Website/tree/296d25921afe5480c5c525caae18fe82df1766f4?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">RAW HTML</a> generated by <a href="https://stackedit.io/?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">Stackedit</a> using <a href="https://pages.cloudflare.com/?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">CloudFlare Pages</a>. It took about an hour to set up. I moved to Jekyll after getting annoyed at having to replicate changes to the footer and head on multiple markdown pages.</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Removing the Audio Jack was a Mistake]]></title><description><![CDATA[I recently upgraded my Pixel 4a to 6a, but to my shock and horror, there was no audio jack.]]></description><link>https://www.bitsbipsbricks.com/removing-the-audio-jack-was-a-mistake/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">639e1805ccda4c003da017d2</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2022 01:11:04 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1513612828366-aee99066bb06?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=MnwxMTc3M3wwfDF8c2VhcmNofDF8fHBob25lJTIwd2l0aCUyMGRvbmdsZXxlbnwwfHx8fDE2NzEzMjU1ODM&amp;ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;q=80&amp;w=2000" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1513612828366-aee99066bb06?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=MnwxMTc3M3wwfDF8c2VhcmNofDF8fHBob25lJTIwd2l0aCUyMGRvbmdsZXxlbnwwfHx8fDE2NzEzMjU1ODM&amp;ixlib=rb-4.0.3&amp;q=80&amp;w=2000" alt="Removing the Audio Jack was a Mistake"><p>I recently upgraded my Pixel 4a to 6a. I&apos;m a big fan of Pixel&apos;s solid hardware, clean stock Android (with Pixel UI) and great price.</p><p>I assumed the 6a would have an audio jack, just like the 4a. But to my shock and horror, it didn&apos;t. One of the robotics team coaches at my high school&#x2014; an engineer for GM for 35 years, would say, &quot;When you assume you make an arse out of you and me&quot;. I was certainly made into an arse.</p><p>So I begrudgingly went to Best Buy to buy the cheapest Google wireless earbuds&#x2014;the Google Pixel Buds A Series, for $80. I came back home and used them inside for a couple of hours. They&apos;re okay. Not the best, but useable.</p><p>I then decided to go for a walk. I put the earbuds in their case and the case in my pocket. When I came back home, the case was not in my pocket. I am now legitimately pissed off. After searching my house, I realized I had probably dropped them when pulling out my wallet. I got some <a href="https://www.heirloomtoronto.com/cheesecake-on-a-stick?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com">cheesecake on a stick</a>. The case was on top of my wallet in my pocket. I hadn&apos;t set up my tap properly yet. So I quickly took out my wallet to pay. And the case probably fell out, and I didn&apos;t hear it over the loud music.</p><h2 id="tradeoffs">Tradeoffs</h2><p>Everything in life is about tradeoffs. Saying that something should be different without considering constraints is just magical thinking.</p><p>I understand that the phone can be thinner and have a longer battery life without the audio jack. I understand the Bluetooth is good enough to stream quality audio now. I understand that the goal is to eventually remove the charging port. But I still want my audio jack!</p><figure class="kg-card kg-image-card kg-card-hascaption"><a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/Kanye/comments/84ijrz/easily_my_favorite_kanye_tweet?ref=bitsbipsbricks.com"><img src="https://www.bitsbipsbricks.com/content/images/2022/12/KanyeTweet.png" class="kg-image" alt="Removing the Audio Jack was a Mistake" loading="lazy" width="666" height="468" srcset="https://www.bitsbipsbricks.com/content/images/size/w600/2022/12/KanyeTweet.png 600w, https://www.bitsbipsbricks.com/content/images/2022/12/KanyeTweet.png 666w"></a><figcaption>From Kanye West&apos;s Twitter via Reddit user _the_orange_box_</figcaption></figure><h2 id="why">Why?</h2><p>I don&apos;t think the tradeoffs are worth it. I am willing to have a larger and thicker phone. I&apos;d love more battery life, but I care much more about my mental battery than my phone&apos;s. Relative to my $15 wired earbuds, wireless earbuds are more expensive, are easier to fall out of my ear, are easier to lose individually, and take up more space in my pocket. And it&apos;s easier to lose them even in the case, as I found out.</p><p>Now I have to walk around with a dongle attached to my wired earbuds. And I can&apos;t charge my phone while using earbuds.</p><p>I understand that some people are willing to make these tradeoffs. And maybe flagship phones shouldn&apos;t have an audio jack, but the Pixel A series definitely should. (But I secretly believe all of you agree with me. Memetic desire has got you believing that you&apos;d be cool if you were wearing AirPods)</p><p>All I want is a stock Android phone with an audio jack. Google, why won&apos;t you take my money?</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Text to Speech and Podcast Ads]]></title><description><![CDATA[<h3 id="hey-myke-please-use-your-code-justformyke">Hey Myke, Please Use Your Code, JustForMyke</h3><p>There are two types of podcast ads &#x2014; static and dynamic.</p><p>For static ads, the ad doesn&#x2019;t change, it&#x2019;s the same for everyone. They&#x2019;re the podcast ads we know and love, the host we&#x2019;ve listened</p>]]></description><link>https://www.bitsbipsbricks.com/text-to-speech-and-podcast-ads/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">63013315d53e0e004db1a447</guid><dc:creator><![CDATA[Ram]]></dc:creator><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2022 20:03:52 GMT</pubDate><media:content url="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1487537023671-8dce1a785863?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=MnwxMTc3M3wwfDF8c2VhcmNofDE0fHxwb2RjYXN0fGVufDB8fHx8MTY2MTAyMzMzMQ&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;w=2000" medium="image"/><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h3 id="hey-myke-please-use-your-code-justformyke">Hey Myke, Please Use Your Code, JustForMyke</h3><img src="https://images.unsplash.com/photo-1487537023671-8dce1a785863?crop=entropy&amp;cs=tinysrgb&amp;fit=max&amp;fm=jpg&amp;ixid=MnwxMTc3M3wwfDF8c2VhcmNofDE0fHxwb2RjYXN0fGVufDB8fHx8MTY2MTAyMzMzMQ&amp;ixlib=rb-1.2.1&amp;q=80&amp;w=2000" alt="Text to Speech and Podcast Ads"><p>There are two types of podcast ads &#x2014; static and dynamic.</p><p>For static ads, the ad doesn&#x2019;t change, it&#x2019;s the same for everyone. They&#x2019;re the podcast ads we know and love, the host we&#x2019;ve listened to for dozens of hours makes an authentic recommendation for a product they use and then implores you to use their promo code. Because of the host&#x2019;s relationship with the audience, these ads are effective and convert well. The right podcaster with a podcast about the right topic can support themselves full time with an audience of just thousands. But the fact that the ads can only be targeted to the listeners of the podcast as a whole means that the product usually needs mass appeal, e.g. Casper mattresses or Squarespace web hosting. As a result, static podcast ads might not work for smaller companies or niche products. This is doubly true for more popular podcasts because it&#x2019;s the same ad for all listeners, only large advertisers can afford to pay to reach the entire audience.</p><p>For dynamic ads, the ad is customized for you, either at download time or stream time. For download time ads, when you download the podcast, the podcast&#x2019;s ad network will select what they think is the best ad for you based on your IP address, location, when you are downloading the episode, and any other info they can determine about you. The ad is then inserted into the audio file that you download. It&#x2019;s usually an ad recorded by a different person trying to sell a product, similar to how ads work on YouTube. It&#x2019;s obvious when you download the back catalog of an old podcast, and it&#x2019;s all the same ads, despite the podcast being several years old.</p><p>Streaming time dynamic ads are the same as download time ads, except that the ad is picked when you are listening to the podcast and that the same company runs the podcast ad network as your podcast player (i.e. Spotify). Because your podcast player is inserting the ad, they know a lot more about you, what type of products and ads you respond to, and critically if you listened to the ad.</p><p>In the past, the trade-off between static and dynamic ads was that you could have really high-performing, authentic but untargeted ads or better targeted, more corporate-sounding dynamic ads. But modern Text-to-Speech removes the trade-offs. TTS has improved quite rapidly, with a small audio sample, modern TTS can generate audio almost indistinguishable from the podcasters&#x2019; real voice. Audio production was once expensive, but now with AI, it can be cheap.</p><p>In the near future, dynamically inserted ads will not be generic corporate ads but targeted and customized to you, read to you in the podcast host&#x2019;s voice. If the cost of generating audio is cheap, the ad network won&#x2019;t just choose the product and pitch that resonates the most for you but could also generate custom promo codes targeted for you. For example, if you&#x2019;re streaming your podcast or if the podcast uses individualized feeds, you could be hearing, &#x201C;Hey Myke, use your promo code, JustForMyke to get 10% off beard oil&#x201D;.<br></p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>